Stay in your lane and start like hack
hard, okay? Don't listen to all of the
chatter about, oh, you know, Justin's
got 50 bucks on this app. No, ignore
that. Pick your portion of the scope,
lock in, and find a [__] ton of bugs.
Best part of when you can just, you
know, critical thing, right?
Yeah, dude.
[Music]
Sup hackers. Uh super lightweight this
week in bug bounty segment for this
week. We just have a new program
announcement on Yes, We Hack and that is
going to be Decathlon. Um and so if any
of you guys are uh you know outdoorsy
type, you're probably familiar with this
brand. They just went public on Yes We
Hack. And of course, Yes We Hack doesn't
do VDPs. So, this is of course a book
bounty program. Um, and you know, like
we always talk about, maybe a good idea
to hack brands you're familiar with or
that you've used. So, if you're uh if
you're using any of their their
equipment, then could be cool to check
out. They've got WW and scope for all of
their um TLDDs uh across all the
different languages. Um so, check them
out if you're interested in uh popping
that that brand. All right, let's go
back to the show.
All righty, subpackers. This week, uh,
Brezzo and I are both going on vacation,
so we're doing a little bit of a
separate pre-record, and I've got an
episode for you guys on how to succeed
at live hacking events. That's been one
of my things that I focused on in my
career as a bug bounty hunter is how do
you perform consistently at these live
hacking events? Cuz the opportunities
are amazing and I want to continue going
to them. So recently I was working with
one of my mentees, Gret, the guy that
runs the hackerotes for critical
thinking and um I sat down with him
during one of our sessions as he was
going into his first live hacking event
and gave him some advice on uh how how
to succeed at the live hacking event.
And my boy crushed it, guys. My boy
crushed it. And uh I selfishly, of
course, I'm going to take credit for
that. No. Um, Brandon worked really hard
and uh and did a great job, but I did
want to take some of the advice that I
gave him and consolidate it into an
episode for you guys so that if any of
you guys have the opportunity to go to a
live hacking event, um you know how to
crush it. And also, I think a lot of
these principles are really applicable
to uh just how to hack in general with
intensity. So, um we'll kind of go
through those, but first, let's go ahead
and jump into some of the uh just
research news that's kind of hit the
scene over the past couple days. I'm
going to go ahead and share my screen.
The first one that's up is uh yet
another post from Jorian. Um this guy
has been crushing it uh with research
lately. And this one sort of piggybacks
off of uh Paulos uh research uh on
double clickjing. Um and and I think
makes it makes it quite good. Um the
title of this one is the ultimate double
clickjing PC. For those of you on
YouTube, I'm sharing my screen. Um, and
it's it's just a combination of a lot of
different factors and stuff we've talked
about on the podcast. So, I wanted to go
ahead and show it. Uh, I'm gonna
actually play the the PC video here
while I'm talking about it so that you
guys can see on YouTube. Um, really
really well done. Essentially, this
technique sort of combines uh the
research of double clickjacking along
with uh window.move to to to hijack the
click um and a pop under that we've
talked about from uh a couple weeks back
from Renoa um using the signin with
Google uh functionality that's sort of
embedded into Chrome to cause a popup to
get pushed behind a window. And then he
simulates it with a flappy bird's uh
game where you know you're click click
click click to make the bird jump and
then when you need to make him jump high
of course you double click and that's
when uh your GitLab account gets pawned.
Um so really really awesome PC here by
Jorian. If you guys want to if you guys
ever had the opportunity to uh build out
something like this uh then this could
be a great place to start um taking a
look at that. Um the the explanation
here is very thorough. you can see
exactly how everything works with the
with the move to. Um that's why he uses
the pop under is to, you know, get
everything in place uh and ready for
when you need to hijack the click. Um
and just really really good work. And
also shout out to Renoa for the um for
the pop under. Um yeah, and he also
builds out like the fake Cloudflare
capture. It was it was pretty clean.
Definitely a good read if you're into
client side stuff.
Um, okay. So, next up is uh the
Graphfana CVES that hit recently. Um,
and I am a little bit of a Graphfana
hacker myself. So, whenever something
Graphana comes up, I kind of like to go
back and look at it. I think Grafana is
a really cool codebase where, uh, you
know, it's written in Go. It's pretty
readable. Um, you can go and and you can
go and you can go and audit the code and
kind of attack it. And Graphfana is
pretty much everywhere. like there are
hundreds of instances of graphana uh if
not more out there um in in scope of bug
bounty programs. So it's a really good
target for if you're trying to find um
zero days in a software and then sprayed
across a bunch of bug bounty programs.
It's a really good target. So this guy
Alvaro um goes ahead and documents uh
some of the uh vulnerabilities he found.
Um and we see that it starts with an
open redirect. He kind of goes through
um exactly how he did that by getting a
uh specific um file embedded and then he
hits it eventually he hits it with a um
where's that where's that piece right
here. So here's the open redirect right
here. It's via a slash and then
backslashbased traversal right um which
is something that we see uh quite often.
So this turns into right here this turns
into a absolute URL when normalized by
the browser. So slashbacks slash at the
beginning will turn into slash which is
an absolute URL not a relative. This
this uh sort of relative URL and
absolute uh URL confusion happens really
often and this is one of the more uh
common variations I see. So great work
to finding the open redirect and then he
he changed that changed that into full
read SSRF by hitting the render endpoint
on graphana. Um and he's able to do a
lots of other stuff with it as well.
Some client side path traversal. Um, so
it's just a good a good summary of how
exactly to chain an open redirect inside
of these uh environments. And he gets uh
$3,700 for it. Um, he does say, however,
that uh this one isn't really uh great
for spraying to multiple book bounty
programs since the exploitation paths
require authentication. But to be
honest, I would also just I would send
it out just in case. You know, if you
can build a PC and you're very confident
that your PC will work if somebody
authenticated clicks on it, then um
yeah, why not? But there could be some
nuance to the situation here. Anyway,
it's a good read. Maybe check out
Grafana if you're interested in doing
some zeroday research on an open source
project that also has big bug bounty
implications. Um, oh, also, yeah, he
dropped the uh exploit as well. We'll
link it in the description, but he
dropped the exploit for that on GitHub
as well on his uh on his GitHub uh CVE
20254123. So, you can check that out
there. All right, last last piece on the
news is Evan Conny's write up um on his
first 100 bugs that he found uh on
Hacker One. Um and I just love these
sort of data like reports, right? like
these where people take all of their
reports, they conglomerate all the data
together, they sort it by type, they
talk about their strengths and
weaknesses as a hacker. Um, I just think
this is a really profitable read for
anybody who's into Bug Bounty. It
doesn't even necessarily have to be the
beginners, though certainly this is uh
very impactful for beginners. So, if you
guys have any friends that are getting
into Bug Bounty or something like that,
might be a good one to forward over to
them. And uh and I let's see if I can
find the um the quote that I really
wanted to talk about here.
Um yeah, he says that moment made
everything click for me. Not just the
adrenaline of finding a critical, but
the realization that you can uncover
impactful issues even outside of the
typical web uh proxy tool flow, right?
And uh this single report gave me the
confidence to treat other programs as
viable targets. And and I think for a
lot of uh hackers, especially if you
guys are mentoring newer hackers, it's
really um it's really impactful to try
to show them and make them believe
tangibly that bugs exist. That's why I
like to do, you know, with my friends
that I'm teaching how to hack. Um, I
like to do these these hackalongs where
we have I have a vone uncovered already,
like a low or something like that on one
of these programs and then I guide them
to finding it during the hacking
session. And sometimes I I don't have
time to prep that in advance, but um
I've done it once or twice where I have
and uh it's it's just great to see the
it click in their in their in their
brain like, "Oh yeah, wow. I just found
a security vulnerability. I can hack
this." Um, so cool ideas there to
implement with your friends if you're
interested. Um, and it costs a couple
hundred bucks, right? You know, you're
going to lose the low or whatever, but
it it adds a lot more value to your
friends, so it it's worth it for me. I
love these graphs here talking about the
severity distribution, the type
distribution, and of course, I love the
shout out that he gives us at the end
saying, "Check out the critical thinking
podcast and Discord community." Dude,
Evelyn, I appreciate you, man. Thank you
so much for being an active part of our
community. Um, and I also do echo what
he says here about uh Reddit bug
bounties r/bug bounty Reddit. Uh, it's
there's a lot of jaded people out there
and, you know, I can't blame them in in
some capacity because it is very much a
punch in the gut when you try to submit
something to Bug Bounty and a triager
says, you know, f off or whatever and
you just can't get a bug. Um, or you get
dupe right on a perfectly valid bug.
Super annoying. and and I could see
people get jaded and not have the um you
know the gumption the stick to itness to
keep pushing pushing pushing. Um but
that's what we try to talk about here on
the pot, right? We try to show you that
consistent and high quality success like
Evans here in the Vagani world is
totally possible if you just keep
pushing pushing pushing and understand
the rules of the game um and and keep
keep giving it your full effort. So
anyway, great great write up by Evan.
definitely check it out uh and pass it
on to some newer hackers as well. Um
love this section, advice for newer
hackers as well. Okay, so that's the
news. Let's go ahead and move over to um
the main topic of today's episode, which
is how to win at live hacking events.
Now, I'll just spend a moment giving
some of my credentials for this. Um I
have won four live hacking events, two
Hacker One events, two uh Google events.
Um, and freaking Fron Rosen keeps uh
oneupping me. So, I think there are a
couple people I I don't hold the top um
spot for most live hacking events. One
uh but I I've I've done this a couple
times and I've participated in probably
30 plus live hacking events. Um and so I
do have a little bit of a system here
for how to how to win at these, how to
perform well at least. And and also let
me say I have like eight second place
trophies. Like uh which is super
annoying to me. Uh but you know, my goal
is consistently to try to rank in the
top five. If if I'm in the top 10, I'm
not going to be sad. Uh but if I'm below
the top 10, I'm like, I hacked something
up. I got to figure out what I did
wrong. So um let me take some of the
pieces of the methodology that I've
developed over the years and give it to
you
guys. Okay. So I'm going to break this
out into several sections. First is
going to be pre-event. Then we're going
to move into scope call or post scope
call. We're going to move to the uh dupe
window uh end which is signals a big
change in how you should approach the
targets. The on-site and the day of the
event. Um so let's go ahead and go
through each one of these. So first
pre-event you get your invite um
typically through the hacker one panel
or an email or something like that. Um
and you've got a timeline now and you
don't typically know the target at this
point. Um, but you know, maybe sometimes
you hear through the grapefine what the
target's going to be. A lot of people
will go and start trying to hack on that
target and become familiar with that
target and come with bugs in their
pocket to the live hacking
event. I personally don't do this
because I think it's a high-risk thing
to do. Um, I prefer to focus on, you
know, the ways to optimize my earnings
and I don't think that spending time on
this target, you know, before I know
what's in scope or what's not in scope
is probably the best way to optimize my
earnings. So, I don't do that, but be
aware that some people may do that and
that, you know, people may have a
critical on an inscope asset in their
pocket on days day one, you know, as
soon as the the scope call is over. Um,
so, you know, weigh your options there.
you really really want to perform at
this event and it's like your your life
goal and you're not really optimizing
for money, you're optimizing for this,
then you may want to start, you know,
try to put some feelers out, see if
anybody knows the target and then uh
start pre-hacking is if they have a bug
bounty program where stuff is in scope.
Um, okay, here's where stuff gets a
little bit controversial. Okay, I am
going to recommend uh or my I'm not even
going to recommend it. I'm going to tell
you guys that my approach is not to
collab before the the dupe window ends.
Okay? And the reason for that is because
I think that uh I find a lot of bugs
before the dupe window ends. And if I am
splitting those with other hackers, uh
then it doesn't normally work out in my
in my favor from a financial
perspective. And I've tried this many
many different ways, many many different
times. It just doesn't typically work
out in my in my favor. So, what I
typically do is I lock in for the uh
between when the event starts and when
the dupe window ends. I should back up.
What is the dupe window? The dupe window
is a period of time after the uh live
hacking event starts where if people
dupe on each other, the reward gets
split across all the hackers. Okay. Um,
and if you are collaborating with other
hackers, right, then you're you get a
and and that when report is duped, then
you get a split of a split and these
things get really really small really
really fast, which is very demoralizing.
So, um, I personally don't collab before
the dupe window ends. Um, there are
people that very successfully do this
and they are com they are very invested.
All of the people on the team are very
invested in spending the same amount of
time hacking, right? Working very hard.
Um, and my advice to people that would
be willing to do full split collabs with
other hackers from the very beginning is
collab with a hacker you feel inferior
to or or a hacker that has a very
different skill set than you, right? Um,
that way you're not going to feel like
there's some sort of um overlap there or
or if somebody is not as invested with
you as you, you're not going to feel
like, oh, I put, you know, 40 hours into
this while they put 20. I'm getting I'm
getting jipped out of the situation.
Okay? And at the end of the day, if you
do commit to a collab, commit to the
collab and don't don't take a ledger,
you know, but you you should use it to
inform future decisions, but don't hold
it against the other collaborators. Does
that make sense? Hope hopefully so. All
right. Uh so I personally don't collab
before the 2.0. Two, uh lock in. Okay. I
I always say this to people. If this if
you're doing a live hacking event, you
should take it very seriously. Um when I
had a job, a W2 job, I would take time
off of work unpaid because I'm going to
make more money at at this than I am at
my work anyway. Um and get really
serious about it. Uh what does it mean
to get serious about it? Well, what I
often do is preload time with my wife,
with my kids, with my chores, right? I
try to, you know, take my wife out on a
couple dates, make sure her her love
meter is at 10 out of 10, right? Going
into this because I'm going to be really
focused on work for the next couple
weeks. Same thing with the kids. Make
sure you do something fun with them.
Make sure that they, you know, know that
you care about them so that you are when
you're locked in here, they're not
running on zero, you know, in their
tank. Um, and then try to knock out any
chores or logistic things that might get
in the way. You know, if you've if
you've got you need if the lawn needs to
be cut, cut it. Um, if you need to do
your taxes, get them knocked out before
the live hacking event so that you can
stay locked in and not be distracted by
other things um during that
time. Okay. And here's another one that
is really important, guys. One of the
very
um impactful things about the live
hacking event is how competitive it is,
right? I would strongly recommend to you
not to look at the leaderboard. Do not
look at the stats near the bounty brief.
Do not pay attention to the hackers in
the Slack that are like, "Excuse me,
could I get a could I get a triage on,
you know, number one, two, three or
whatever because it's a critical and I
really want you to get it done quick
because users are at
risk." They're just flexing, dude.
They're flexing. Okay? And that's going
to do nothing but make you feel bad
about your findings if you haven't had a
critical. Okay? So, uh, don't do that.
Stay in your lane and start like hack
hard. Okay? Don't listen to all of the
chatter about, oh, you know, Justin's
got 50 bugs on this app. No, ignore
that. Pick your portion of the scope.
Lock in and find a [__] ton of bugs.
Okay? Also, inversely, don't flex on
other hackers. Okay? If you do find a
crit, don't be that guy that like puts
it in the channel and is like, "Hey
guys, I got a crit on this one. Could
you get a f?" You know, no. Just be
sportsmanlike. Lock in hack stuff.
Present yourself with humility.
Okay. Um Okay. So, that's sort of
pre-event
stuff. I guess the ignoring the other
hackers is kind of after the event
starts, but I could I'll move that to my
next section. Let's talk about the scope
call. Okay. What the scope call is the
kickoff call that occurs when you are uh
starting the live hacking event. There
will typically be a period of time where
um you know they'll do a presentation.
They'll talk about the bonuses. They'll
talk about the increased rewards.
They'll talk about the scope right for
the event, what what targets you can uh
hack on. They'll give you access to like
accounts. Uh that sort of thing. Um,
yeah. What I would recommend to you here
is focus on two things for the scope
call. What does the team want me to hack
on? What is going to make them go, "Oh
[__] if I if I pop that, right?" That's
what you should probably be hacking on.
However, you you need to balance that a
little bit with anticipated interest
from other hackers because it does suck
when you get a bunch of dupes. So, what
I typically go for is something that is
tier zero, right? So something that is
extremely valuable to the program, but
probably like tier one or tier two on
interest with other hackers, right?
Other hackers are maybe a little
intimidated by it or maybe don't think
it's as featurerich as it could be,
something like that, right? Um I don't
typically go for tier zero interest zero
because that's going to get a lot of a
lot of uh other um interest from other
hackers. Um all right, then the next
thing that I'd recommend is something
that I call pick your portion. Okay. So,
look at the scope that they've presented
to you and you got to you got to pick,
you know, what piece of that app you
want to cover or or what piece of this
this company you want to cover because
typically the scope is going to be
pretty wide and you're not going to be
able to cover all of it with enough
depth. That's just the way these things
work. Okay. Um, so what I typically do
is I pick one app and I say, "All right,
I'm going to go ham on this app for the
next like couple days." Um, and as soon
as the po the the scope call is over,
make a snap decision on what that is and
try to go try all of the impactful
semi-obvious scenarios over the past or
over the next like couple hours. Like,
you know, the one that pops to my mind
is freaking host headerbased uh password
reset link injection, right? where where
you change the host header, that host
header gets put into a password reset
link that was generated and it goes into
someone's email and now you've got
account takeover, you know, zero click
or technically maybe one click atto. Um,
try all that stuff for the first uh, you
know, couple hours because you want to
try to pop those uh, as early as
possible.
Um, yeah. And then after those couple
hours, you should, you know, just from
the feel of the app when you're in there
trying all those other things, you
should have an idea on whether your snap
decision was a valid decision or not on
on like is there enough scope here for
me to focus on it for like 4 to 5 days
at least um you know maybe 10 hours a
day uh or do I need to switch to
something else. You have one opportunity
here to switch to another piece of
scope. Okay. Once you switch, you must
stick to that scope. Do not get
distracted by the shiny objects. Okay?
Stay locked in on that piece of scope
until you are the world expert on that
piece of scope. I typically recommend
three times as long as you would
normally spend on an app to spend on
these apps that you're in the live
hacking here because you need to go
deep. You need to go deep deep on these
apps. Okay. Um, so that's kind of what I
would recommend. Um, let me see what I
had something else under this section.
Uh, yeah, like I said, try to pick
something that other hackers might be uh
intimidated by and then uh prioritize
what attack vectors you implement based
off of the attack vector value that I've
talked about in my high ROI bug hunters
talk. If you haven't seen that, it's
available to the critical thinkers in
the critical thinking discord. And I
think there might be a recording
floating around there on YouTube. Uh no,
that was Bugani village uh not the main
uh main stage. So it was not recorded.
So the only recording is in is in the
critical thinkers tier. Well, I'll just
give you a summary of it real quick. The
attack vector value is um well hold on
let me let me just pause it really quick
and grab the the presentation. Okay,
here's the one slide from from that I'm
going to share from this which is uh the
attack vector value. Okay, this is what
I typically uh use to try to decide what
I'm going after. This is the impact and
this attack vector value is is um
defined by the following function. It's
impact times viability divided by
friction. Okay? And this isn't perfect.
This is just how I think about it
currently. So impact would be what is
like the the
the impact of a successful exploitation,
right? Like do I get account takeover?
Do I get like can I leak the you know
query parameters? I don't know. Like
there's a large variety of of impact
that could happen. And then what is the
viability? uh what is the chance that
this will actually work or not right if
it if something about the application
informs us that wow they're super
vulnerable to IDOR and I can see you
know a request that looks like it's
vulnerable to IDOR but it's like super
buried in the application or something
like that the liability is pretty high
that that will actually work right
because we know that they're vulnerable
to IDOR pretty regularly we just got to
get deep into the app to to get it and
speaking of getting deep into the app
that's what friction is right so
friction is the amount of effort to uh
attempt a given attack vector. Um so
impact time viability divided by
friction. Okay? And that's kind of how I
think about these attack vectors. And
don't don't get me wrong, I'm not like
quantifying each attack vector idea that
I come up with. I'm kind of doing this
by vibe mostly in my brain. Um but it
would be really cool to figure out a way
to quantify all these. So maybe
something for you guys to think on. All
right, let me get back to my other
stuff.
Um, yeah. So, prioritize off of those
three variables, impact, um, you know,
viability and
friction. Okay. Now, here's where stuff
gets a little bit, uh, counterintuitive.
Okay. Um, during the live hacking event,
you may be,
uh, inclined, especially if you're super
locked in, to not eat, not drink, not
exercise, not get any sunshine, not get
any sleep. Right? I'm looking at you,
Ronnie Carter, Mr. Lupin over there, Mr.
Allnighter. Um, I would really not
recommend this. Your brain will not be
functioning at top capacity and you can
say, "Oh, I'm one of those people where
no, you're not like that's just not how
human biology works." Like, it it
doesn't. Um, so really try to get good
quality food, try to get water, get in
some some exercise and sunshine. you're
going to your brain will be functioning
better and get however much sleep you
need. Okay? You know there is variance
in how much sleep people need but you do
need some sleep. I guarantee that. So um
don't neglect those things. I am not a
perfect example of this. I do not feed
myself during live hacking events. U my
wife very graciously will bring me food
while I'm hacking because I I just for
some reason for the life of me cannot
remember to eat or drink while I'm
hacking. Um, but we have a system for
that, right? My wife and I partner on
that and um, and she helps with that. As
far as exercise and sunshine goes, I go
for walks and that's something I'll kind
of cover in a little bit, but you need
to take time away. Well, we can just
cover it now. You need to take time away
from the screen and away from
stimulation to let your brain sort of
iterate. I often will go into the hot
tub or go for a walk for those two
things to let my brain start try to um,
come up with different attack vectors or
different ways of approaching a problem.
I've popped multiple crits while sitting
in the hot tub or on a walk. So, it's
very very important, especially ones
that I spent like eight hours staring at
my screen for. I I was so frustrated
about this one time. Like, I knew that
this one vulnerability was exploitable.
And I just stared at my screen for eight
hours and I was like, you know, really
honestly barely doing any typing or or
or reading. I was just mostly like
thinking, but I couldn't figure it out.
And then I go in the hot tub and I solve
it in like 30 minutes. So, so it really
try different environments. Try to get
some exercise. Try to get some sunshine.
Okay. Um, yeah. And and then I also say
don't forget to relax a little bit
during these events. If you're taking my
advice, you're probably going really
hard, but you need to have some
scheduled calculated rest as well. Okay.
I I do this typically on Sunday. I try
to try to follow uh the Christian
biblical principles of Sabbath. um
during the live hacking events. There is
some nuance to that, but I do try to
spend a bit of time on those Sundays
relaxing and, you know, detentionizing
myself. Um,
okay. Now, I'm going to give you a
little bit of conflicting advice with
that. If there is something that pulls
you away from
hacking, have your brain running on that
hacking stuff while you're away. If
you're in the shower, if you're on the
toilet, if you're running an errand, you
know, be thinking about the app. Think
about attack vector ideation. Have uh
notebook LLM or whatever read you the
docs, right? If you're out somewhere, if
you're waiting like at a doctor's
appointment or in line at the grocery
store, scroll through the docs. Read the
docs. You know, you you need to really,
you know, eat and breathe and sleep on
this application for the next uh week or
so. Um, and then while you're doing
this, record attack vector ideas. Record
gadgets. Um, you know, I do it on like
one of these big I've got a bunch of
them right here, but they've got text on
them, so I'm not going to hold them up,
but these big like legal pads, these
yellow legal pads. That just helps me
think, even though my handwriting is
atrocious. Um, so have something with
you where you can write that
down. Um, okay. Here's another thing you
need to realize. If you want to win this
live hacking event, you need to find at
least one critical. So, one of the
mistakes I've made in the past that I
noted down for myself was I wanted
volume and coverage, but I didn't go
after high high attack vector um targets
enough. Okay, so there was one app or
one event in particular I'm thinking of.
Not going to disclose the company, but
every single freaking endpoint on this
company was vulnerable. So, I was like,
"All right, I'm going to cover all of
these." And it ate up all my time. Um,
and I got like 40 mediums, but I didn't
win that event because I didn't
get enough criticals. I came in
second. Hurts me. Um, so don't make that
same mistake I did. Make sure you're
going for high impact bugs at these live
hacking events because that's really one
of the
differentiators. Okay, that being said,
once you've picked your portion, you
must cover all the core functionality.
dig through the JS files, configure the
app, do whatever you have to do to
become the world expert on this. Do not
neglect O. That is one thing that I have
kind of done in the past. Okay, do not
neglect the uh authentication
mechanisms. We spend a lot of time um
checking authorization most of the time
as hackers, but authentication is
sometimes a little bit scary. Don't
neglect it. Assess it. Um, and then more
than ever, and once again, I know that
this is in juxaposition with what I just
said about finding criticals, but you
need to double down on any weaknesses
you found. And that's what I thought I
was doing in that live hacking event,
right? I said, "Oh, wow. Every
vulnerable, every endpoint's vulnerable
to Idor. I'm going to report every
single idor." Um, and you should
definitely do that, but you also can't
do that to the neglect of high impact
vulnerabilities. Uh, you know, not to
say that those are mutually exclusive,
but you know what I'm saying.
um double down on any weaknesses you
find. Spend time thinking why was this
specific endpoint vulnerable? Why why is
this a application acting so quirky in
this specific scenario, right? Got to
think through all those things. Okay,
once you've really like covered all the
main functionality of your your portion
that you picked, then you go deep into
peripheral assets, SDKs, legacy stuff,
staging assets, mobile apps, Chrome
extensions, APIs, you know, XML based
garbage, you know, like everything that
you can find on this app and and do some
like past recon on this app too to
understand like what the app looked like
as it evolved over time.
go deep deep deep deep into those. Okay.
And then so uh the last section that I
had here while we were in um the actual
like scope post scope call pre-dup
window end portion was just a quick
shout out to Joseph's uh recent write up
that that we'll put in the description.
Uh root for your friends, right? If
you're if you are working with people,
you know, even if you're working not not
collabing with them, but you're like in
the live hacking event with them, like
root for them as much as you can. Like I
said, try to try to not give yourself
the input, especially if you're hyper
competitive and tend to get down on
yourself if you're not performing as
well. Try not give yourself input on how
other hackers are doing, but if you see
it, push your brain to respond
positively, like, "Hell yeah, my boy
Joseph just popped a crit. Let's go."
You know, that sort of thing, right?
Rather than like, "Oh man, I don't have
a crit." You know what am I going to do?
No. Root for your friends. Take that as
motivation. Okay. Um, now you know that
there's a crit out there, right? You can
go find it, too. Okay. Things change a
little bit when the dupe window ends.
This is typically like a week or so.
Um, I don't know the actual duration.
I'm just normally like, all right, set
set a calendar entry. Go. Um, but when
the dupe window ends, you know, things
change a little bit. I typically open
myself up to collaboration a little bit
more. I try I try to finish most of my
stuff by the time the due the due period
ends. And I and I submit most everything
that that I have, you know, especially
if I'm unfamiliar with a company's
threat model and what they may or may
not consider a vulnerability. You don't
really get NAS at live hacking events.
So submit what you've got and you know
they may inform it of you and it's not
the end of the world. you know, um if
you're at a live hacking event, you've
probably got enough rep in stuff where
your signal in or impact or whatever can
take a little bit of a hit. Okay, so
don't stress out about that.
Um yeah, so you know, if for whatever
reason I wasn't able to like exploit
some gadgets or um maybe I've got like
half vulnerabilities that are just very
close to being exploitable, that's when
you kind of reach out to some other
hackers and kind of get a feel for
what's going on. you see what kind of
success they've had on what um other
pieces of scope. You see uh you try to
compare notes. to try to give add value
to the other hacker by like hey here's
this vulnerability
like does this is my takeaway from this
vulnerability right you're trying to add
value to other hackers at that point
okay um and and I also want to say trade
value right if somebody comes to you and
says hey man you know I know you're
looking at this scope I figured out how
to like decrypt this really important
thing dude thank you so much like hold
on let me grab something for you you
know get them a you an equivalent trade
of value as far as information goes
those in the live hacking event. Just
realized my little circle light is off
there. My bad. Um yeah, so try to get
them an equivalent trade of value,
right? Um so that you are adding value
to your other hackers as well. Um pay
very close attention to what you missed.
Man, I'll never forget this one live
hacking event where freaking inhibitor
181 and I spent the entire event on the
same scope and didn't have almost any
overlapping
vulnerabilities. Crazy. And I just the
stuff that I missed and he way out
hacked me at at that event like crazy.
Um the stuff that I missed I will never
ever ever ever ever miss again ever
because of the pain in my heart from
what he found, right? Um and that that
pain can help you learn, right? But you
got to also redirect that in a positive
way. Like, you know, dab up your boy, be
like, "Yo, well done, dude." You know,
that sort of thing.
Um, all right. Uh, let's see. Yeah, find
hackers who have hacked on similar scope
and compare notes. That's kind of what I
was saying there. Also, um, I I'll add
this piece. Try to collaborate fairly
uh, in this in this post um, dupe window
collaboration stuff. Now, now I open
myself up to
collaboration. You want to you want
to if someone if somebody gave you
something, you want to offer them at
least, you know, 5 or 10%, right, of the
vulnerability. That's a minimum. If
somebody if somebody um but you really
want do want to be fair. A lot of people
will be like, "Oh man, if you even give
this little bit, then it's 50/50." And
I'm like, "I don't think so. I don't
think that's the best way to deal with
this." Right? It doesn't feel great from
my side when I do that to other people.
And it doesn't feel great when I'm on
the on the the giving side of that
either. So, I I I try to say, "Hey,
here's the number. I really value
honesty. Give me your thoughts." You
know, and we're all professionals here.
We can negotiate. Um, and then what I
would ask is that you advocate for
yourself fairly and honestly and I'm not
going to take it personally, right?
That's what we that's what we do. And
then at the end of the day, you know, if
there is conflict, know that your
relationship with the other hacker is
more valuable than this specific bounty
because if you're going to be on the
live hacking event scene, uh, that
hacker will definitely have something
you need at some point and, uh, the, you
know, you don't want to burn that
bridge. Also, just don't be a bad
person. That too. Okay, cool. All right,
so that's kind of like the post dupe
window collaboration. There's not much
actually that happens after the uh dupe
window closes besides you know more
collaboration um and you know things
start getting triaged which is cool. Um
but you're really you you stay locked
in. you know, if if you have fully
covered your target and you have um you
know, 3x the time that you would spend
on that target, then switch to a
different target and do that same
methodology, right? Um or maybe a
peripheral target, right? Something that
is tangentally related to the
application you're already hacking. So,
you can reuse some of that knowledge.
Okay, next section is on-site. So, um,
some of you guys may not be
participating in an on-site live hacking
event, but it is very, very tricky to
stay locked in when you are on site
because your friends are around, you're
meeting people for the first time,
you're surrounded by hackers that are of
similar skill level, and you're and it's
freaking great. Like, that is why we
made this Joel and I started this
podcast way back in 2023 was because we
freaking love that environment and we
want to bring some of that hype and
energy to you guys every single week.
Okay. Um, that being said, if you really
want to win and you really want to
perform, you should stay locked in on
site. A lot of people, you arrive, you
know, you do the meet and greet or
whatever, and then people will just like
drop their laptops and go out drinking
and party and then stay up till 3 and
get super drunk and be hung over the
next day and it just like it it
cascades. Those people are can do
whatever they want. No judgment here,
but if you want to win, don't do that.
Yeah. And I think if you want to win
you, or if you really are passionate
about hacking, it's really fun to just
grab your laptop and grab a soda or
whatever and go back to your room with
your buddies and be like, "All right,
I'm looking at this. What are you
looking at?" Comparing nodes, hacking on
stuff together. Almost every single
event, if you do this, you will pop a
crit in the hotel room. Like, it just
happens that way. My boy Naggley has
done it like 10 live hacking events in a
row. Um, shout out to my boy Naggley.
Uh, so stay locked in. There will be
more time to play after the live hacking
event is over. Okay. Um, and you want to
kind of optimize your time on site by
utilizing your other hackers that are
present, right? So, if you know your
buddy's really good at this and you got
a lead in that area, maybe just connect
him with that lead, even though if you
think that maybe there's some more time
that you could spend on it.
Um, and plus it feels good to get
momentum going right in the live hack in
the on-site live hack events. Um, so
definitely do that. uh if you have no
leads between you and other hackers,
which is pretty rare, but I have seen it
a couple times, pick a small small piece
of scope to deep dive and try to finish
it all, you know, uh during the on-site
period. Okay. Um this I've done this a
couple times and it has paid out uh for
me pretty well. Um the other thing is
you can do is if there's a meet and
greet and the the team is actually there
that you're hacking, you can go up and
talk to them and be like, "Hey guys,
listen. Um I just kind of finished the
scope that I was hacking on. If you were
in my shoes, where would you look for a
vulnerability? And I did this one time.
I had not hacked on this target at all.
I did this on the day of the live
hacking event. One of the one of the
engineers came up to me. He's like,
"Dude, this area is riddled with bugs.
Go tear it up." And I did exactly what
he said and made like 40 grand. Um, so
shout out to that guy. I don't know if
you remember who you are. This is a long
time ago, but shout out to that guy,
dude, because uh that was amazing. And
there goes all my student loans.
Um, so that that is also a a thing to
do. Talk to the team and also pivoting
into the day of the event sort of
section when you're on site, you know,
on the event on the event day, talk to
the triagers. Advocate for your bugs.
Okay, a lot of people uh are not doing
that when you get on on site. If there
is a bug that's mistriaged or if there
is a, you know, high or critical
vulnerability that you've got in there
that is not getting the attention that
it deserves, um, go like knock on the
war room door and be like, "Hey man,
here's this." And have a prepared PC,
have a, you know, very easy to follow,
um, flow that they can see to quickly
reproduce the bug and triage it. Um, and
that helps them because they don't have
to like get all the context on that bug
and, you know, do it. they can just see
it and follow along with you and it
helps you because now your bug is
triaged and you know on the in the
payout queue for the live hacking event
on the day of. So and if something is
mistriaged then definitely go and knock
on the door and be like yo yo yo this is
hecked this is not a low this is a high
you know this is a crit. Um and and so
advocate for your bugs.
Um if you literally cannot do this find
a friend to do it. I have advocated for
my friends bugs multiple times on their
behalf. Um because I don't know if you
guys know this, but I can talk a little
bit, right? You know, just a tiny bit.
Um so, uh find someone else to do it for
you as
well. Once again, I'll repeat it. Stay
locked in on the day of the live hacking
event. Sit down, hack, hack, hack till
the last minute on the timer. Okay. Uh,
one of the bugs that I am most proud of
I that ever I completed the exploit for
and demoed it for a team of eight eight
team members, right, that were the
program we were hacking on live within
the last hour of the
event. I'm so happy I popped that bug to
this day. And one of my favorite hacking
memories ever is me sitting in this
environment having 18 members from this
massive company behind me and be like,
"Check this out. Boom." and it's like a
mega crit and they're all like, "Oh
shit." Like, you know, it was just it
was the best. It was it was the best,
guys. Stay locked in. You will find cool
stuff at the live hacking event. Okay.
Day of the event. Last thing, pay very
close attention to showand tell. Um, I'm
sorry, not last thing, but close last
thing. Pay very close attention to
showand tell. Show and tell is the
portion where um you know other hackers
will give a presentation on the bugs
that they found that the team selected
because they thought they were the
coolest. Truly reflect on these bugs and
figure out how you could have found them
yourself. Okay? And then really
integrate that into your methodology.
Visualize yourself doing that, right?
And that's how you improve. The other
thing is, you know, showand tell bugs
are great, but guess what? You have
access to unlimited showand tell. If you
go around and you talk to other hackers
and be like, "Hey, can you show me your
bugs and I'll show you mine? Show me
yours and I'll show you mine." Um, and
to be honest, I've learned so much from
that. And most everybody at that live
hacking event is passionate and loves
hacking, right? So, very rarely will
they be like, "Nah, I'm not going to do
it." There there are a couple hackers
that will be like, "Nah, I want to keep
my secrets to myself." But most
everybody's like, "Dude, check this one
out." And they show you one that's
really amazing and blow, you know, blows
your mind. And then, you know, they get
that dopamine hit of having somebody who
also understands how impactful these
vulnerabilities are be like, "Dude, no
way." And then and then, you know, you
get the the knowledge and it's just it's
a win-win. So, talk to other hackers. Uh
freaking Brandon Gret that I mentioned
at the beginning of this does an amazing
job of this. Phenomenal job and it just
makes the growth just skyrocket as a
hacker. Um okay, last little bit um
before I close it out. I know it's
already getting long, especially for a
solo episode.
Um, this is something that's very near
and dear to my heart. Do not define your
identity as a hacker on the outcome of
this live hacking event. Okay? If you
showed up to this live hacking event,
you followed what I said here, you gave
it
110% and you did not rank or you didn't
find a bug, that's okay. All right? It
happens. it. If you follow this
methodology, I think it's probably
pretty rare, but I I'll tell you, I have
had really really bad life hacking
events with like sub 10 bugs. Uh,
and it just happens. Nothing you can do
about it. Doesn't mean you're the worst
hacker. Doesn't mean that you don't
deserve to be there, right? And if you
if you are if you are defining your
identity as a hacker on the outcome of
live hacking event, it's so volatile,
dude. It's so volatile. You could have
just picked the wrong piece of scope.
the asset could be 503ing while you're h
trying to hack it and it's just, you
know, there's so many confounding
variables that could go into place.
Okay, put your identity a as a person
and as a hacker, you know, in something
more stable than live hacking events or
even bug bounties in general because bug
bounties are hella unstable. I've said
this time and time again. I personally
really really struggled with this until
my wife and I had a conversation about,
"Hey, Justin, you're not putting your
identity in Christ," which is where I I
normally try to focus my identity on,
right? Um, as a Christian and after that
conversation with my wife, I have almost
never struggled with that comparison,
that burnout. Um, I I just felt much
more free to enjoy my hacking life when
my identity is in Christ rather than in
my performance as a hacker. Right? And
I'm not going to get all religious on
you guys. You guys can, you know, maybe
Christianity isn't the religion for you.
Maybe, you know, you've got something
else, right? Whatever. But just don't
freaking put it in Bug Bounty, please.
Like, Bug Bounty is volatile as hell.
So, uh, yeah, that's my recommendation
to you. Put your identity in something
more stable. Um, all right, guys. I
think that's about it. You know, if you
if you follow all these, I think you
will have a really, really solid uh live
hacking event. Um, and like I said, many
of these principles are applicable to
outside of bug uh life hacking event as
well, just normal bug bounty, right?
Reflecting on the documentation. Um, you
know, staying locked in, going really
hard, making sure you're taking care of
your responsibilities so that you can
optimize your longer pieces of time as
uh for for bug bounty and staying locked
in on technically complex stuff. Um, so
there's lots of little tidbits there
that you can use um to optimize your
your experience in normal bug bounty as
well. Um, ju just just right before this
episode, there was a little bit of
discussion in the critical thinking
discord about uh rating the show on
Apple Podcast and Spotify, which is
something that I used to ask you guys to
do every every time, but I I just have
kind of forgot now that we've gotten a
couple hundred of them and and we're
pretty well ranked. So, but I'll ask
now. If you guys enjoyed the show,
please give a rating on Apple Podcast
and Spotify. If you're listening on
YouTube, sub on YouTube, drop a comment
for us. That does help the show get some
additional distribution. Um, and of
course, if you're not in the critical
thinking discord, definitely go check it
out. Um, it's a really solid community
as, uh, as Evan said in his write up
that we covered earlier on. Um, and I'm,
to be honest, man, I'm really blown away
by it. I'm really grateful to be in the
critical thinking community because
there are a lot of, um, people there
that are are way more skilled than I am
contributing and adding value. And I'm
just like, wow, this is freaking great.
So, um, would love to see you there. If
you have if you haven't seen, you know,
how to get in there, you can go to
ctv.show, click the Discord link, or
ctb.show/isord if you want to just go
directly to it. Um, all right. I think
that's a wrap. Hope you guys enjoy this
episode, and I'll see you next week.
Peace. And that's a wrap on this episode
of Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to
ctbb.show/isord. You can hop in the
community. There's lots of great
highlevel hacking discussion happening
there. on top of master classes,
hackalongs, exclusive content, and a
full-time hunters guild. If you're a
full-time hunter, it's a great time.
Trust me. All right, I'll see you there.